brentozar.com 2019-09-15

# Privacy Policy for www.BrentOzar.com - Brent Ozar Unlimited®

PRIVACY POLICY for www.BrentOzar.com

This website (the “Website”) is the property of Brent Ozar PLF, LLC, d/b/a Brent Ozar Unlimited (“Ozar,” “we” or “us”). We take the privacy of all visitors to this Website very seriously. Accordingly, this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) sets forth our position regarding certain privacy matters. This Privacy Policy covers all “Personal Data” (as defined below) that is shared by you through the use of this Website, including data affirmatively provided by you or collected via the operation of the Website.  **By visiting and using the Website, you consent and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy**.

### 1\. Information We Collect.

In operating the Website we may collect and process the following data about you (collectively, “Personal Data”):

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website, such as when you register to download any software accessed through our Website (“Software”), receive information from Ozar or subscribe to any Website services;
  * Details of your use of our Website or any Software, including visits to our Website and the resources you access, the number of times the Software is launched, the device IP address, the version of the Software used, Website traffic data, location data, weblog statistics and other communications data;
  * Information that you provide in connection with any support or technical services for the Software;
  * Information required by Ozar to (1) audit your Software usage for anti-piracy purposes; and (2) verify a valid registration, and identify if new updates are available for your server or other computing device prior to notifying you to install a new Software update;
  * Information about transactions carried out over this Website; 
    * Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
    * Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
    * Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!
    * We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.
    * We will track your location based on your IP address in order to monitor for account reuse and send you promotions applicable to your geographic area (like nearby conferences). To detect your location, we will send your IP address to the geolocation services of usersinsights.com. We will store the country, region, city and coordinates associated with your IP address. We will also store your IP address in a hashed format so we can check it for changes.
    * We will track your last login date and number of sessions in order to monitor for account reuse.
    * We will track your browser name, browser version and device platform in order to tailor our site better for your viewing experience.
  * Information provided to us when you communicate with us for any reason.
  * For European Union Residents, information collected and processed is limited to: 
    * Information that you voluntarily provide by filling in forms on our Website, such as when you subscribe to company emails or other marketing communications. By giving us this information, you consent to this information being collected, used, disclosed, transferred to the United States and stored by us, as described in this Privacy Policy.
    * Information that we collect automatically, including the device IP address, location data, browser data and country data. We may collect this information through the use of cookies. Our use of cookies is discussed in more detail below.

### 2\. Use of Your Personal Data.

The Personal Data that we collect and store is primarily used to enable us to provide our services to you, communicate with you per your request, and to enable your access to and use of the Website and/or the Software. In addition, we may use the Personal Data for the following purposes:

  * To meet our contractual commitments to you.
  * To notify you about any changes to our Website, such as improvements or service/product changes, that may affect our service.
  * To allow us to administer the Website;
  * To provide you with information requested from us relating to our products or services;
  * To improve our products and services;
  * To personalize the Website for you.

Further, we may use your Personal Data so that you can be provided with information about goods and services which we consider may be of interest to you. We may contact you about these goods and services by any of the methods that you consented at the time your Personal Data was collected. We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform. By consenting to receiving our communications, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their privacy policy and terms.

If you do not want us to use your data, you will have the opportunity to withhold your consent to this when you provide your details to us on the Website form on which we collect your data.

Please be advised that we do not reveal Personal Data about identifiable individuals to our customers but we may, on occasion, provide them with aggregate statistical information about those who visit our Website.

### 3\. Use of Cookies.

On occasion, Ozar may gather information about your server or other computing device for our services and to provide statistical information regarding the use of our Website to third parties for analytical purposes, as described below. Such information is statistical data about our visitors and their use of our site and will not identify you personally. It is used by us to analyze how visitors to our Website interact with the Website so that we can continue to develop and improve our Website. We may gather information about your general internet use by using a cookie file that is downloaded to your computer. Where used, these cookies are downloaded to your computer automatically.

All computers have the ability to decline cookies. This can be done by activating the setting on your browser which enables you to decline the cookies. Please note that should you choose to decline cookies, you may be unable to access particular parts of our Website.

### 4\. Storing and Protecting Your Personal Data.

We are committed to ensuring that your Personal Data is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of your Personal Data, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the Personal Data we collect online. Ozar operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the Personal Data provided by our customers. Ozar will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your Personal Data. Ozar will transfer and store all your Personal Data on secure servers which may be managed by third parties. Any Personal Data relating to electronic transactions entered into via this Website will be protected by encryption technology. By submitting your Personal Data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

The transmission of Personal Data via the Internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of Personal Data sent to us electronically and transmission of such Data is therefore entirely at your own risk. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password so that you can access certain parts of our site or any of our Software, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

### 5\. Disclosing Your Personal Data.

We will not disclose your Personal Data to third parties except in certain circumstances:

  * Where we used third parties to provide routine support for Ozar’s internal operations, including the delivery and receipt of e-mail or other internet-based communications or the creation of online meetings;
  * Where we sell any or all of our business and/or our assets to a third party;
  * Where we are legally required to disclose your Personal Data; or
  * In order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

Where Ozar discloses your Personal Data to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obligated to use that Personal Data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### 6\. Public Information.

We have public blogs on our Website. Any information you include in a comment on our blog may be read, collected, and used by anyone. If your Personal Data appears on our blogs and you want it removed, contact us at [Help@BrentOzar.com](mailto:Help@BrentOzar.com).

### 7\. Data Retention For European Union Residents.

Upon [your request](https://www.brentozar.com/privacy-policy/about-gdpr-requests/), we will provide you with any of your Personal Data. We will retain your Personal Data for as long as you have consented to receiving our communications or until such time as you request that we cease storing your Personal Data. We may also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and prevent abuse.

### 8\. Third Party Links.

You may find links to third party websites on our Website. These websites may have their own privacy policies which you should review. Ozar does not accept any responsibility or liability for third party websites or the privacy policies referenced therein.

### 9\. Hosting.

This Website is hosted by [WPengine.com](https://wpengine.com/). Certain Personal Data collected by Ozar may be stored by WPengine in accordance with the WPengine.com Privacy Notice, which can be found at <https://wpengine.com/legal/privacy/>.

Your data may also be shared with our other hosting partners:

  * [Automattic](https://automattic.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) – because we filter possible spam comments with Askimet
  * [Calendly](https://calendly.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://calendly.com/pages/privacy) – because you may book a call with us there
  * [Disqus](https://disqus.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) – because we host PasteThePlan comments there
  * [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/) – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) – because we track page popularity and user activity
  * [Google](https://www.google.com/) AMP Cache – [Privacy Policy](https://developers.google.com/amp/cache/policies) – because you may be viewing our pages through their cache
  * [Google](https://www.google.com/) Fonts – [Privacy Policy](https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq#what_does_using_the_google_fonts_api_mean_for_the_privacy_of_my_users) – because we use their fonts to render these pages
  * [GoToWebinar](https://www.gotomeeting.com/webinar) – [Privacy Policy](https://www.logmeininc.com/legal/privacy) – because you may sign up for our webcasts hosted there
  * [Gumroad](https://gumroad.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://gumroad.com/privacy) – because you may buy our products through them
  * [Paypal](https://www.paypal.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) – because you may use their payment methods
  * [Quickbooks/Intuit](https://quickbooks.intuit.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://security.intuit.com/index.php/privacy) – because we bill you through their accounting software
  * [Stripe](https://stripe.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy) – because they process your credit card payments
  * [Vimeo](https://vimeo.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy) – because we embed our training videos on the site
  * [YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/) – [Privacy Policy](https://www.youtube.com/t/privacy) – because we embed YouTube videos on the site

### 10\. Controlling your Personal Data.

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your Personal Data in the following ways:

Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the Website, refrain from opting in to having your Personal Data be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes;

If you have previously agreed to us using your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time [with this form](https://www.brentozar.com/privacy-policy/about-gdpr-requests/) or by notifying us by e-mail at [Help@BrentOzar.com](mailto:Help@BrentOzar.com) and we will erase it;

If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us at [Help@BrentOzar.com](mailto:Help@BrentOzar.com). We will promptly correct any Personal Data found to be incorrect.

### 11\. Other Information.

If you are a European Union Resident and have an unresolved privacy or personal information collection, use, or disclosure concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact the EU Data Protection Authorities. For more information on how to contact the EU Data Protection Authorities, please visit: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>

### 12\. Contacting Us.

We welcome any queries, comments or requests you may have regarding this Privacy Policy. Please do not hesitate to contact us at [Help@BrentOzar.com](mailto:Help@BrentOzar.com).

If you prefer to write to us then our contact address is:

Brent Ozar Unlimited  
PO Box 29502, ECM #45779  
Las Vegas, NV 89126-9602

### 13\. Updating this statement.

Ozar may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this Website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are familiar with any changes. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will supersede this version of our Policy.
